Guide to the Larry Polansky Papers MSS.405
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I. Compositions and Arrangements, 1975-2013; 22 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 13 manuscript boxes, 8 tall manuscript boxes, 3 flat boxes, and 5 oversize flat boxes; 7.37 Gigabytes in 1,742 computer files.; 70 audiocassettes; 48 sound cassettes (dat); 57 Reels
  - A Very Slow Lament for Solo Oboe / Onion Skin, 1981; cuid25368 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - V'leem ' Shol, 1988; cuid25367 (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Will You Miss Me, 1981; cuid25724 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - The World's Longest Melody, 1992-2009; cuid25312 (Box 8, Folder 19-21, Box 73, Folder 19)
  - Yitgadal, 1999, 2004-2005; cuid25313 (Box 8, Folder 22-24, Box 73, Folder 20, Box 78, Folder 12)
  - You Can Count on Me, Phil, 1980; cuid25314 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Series II. Event Ephemera, 1976-2013; 9 Linear Feet in 9 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 1 flat-file folder; 1.19 Gigabytes in 6 computer files.; 18 audiocassettes; 29 sound cassettes (dat)
  Arranged in alphabetical order by file title and chronologically within.
  This series contains ephemera documenting Polansky's career as a performer and lecturer through concert and event programs, flyers, announcements, posters, and audiovisual recordings. These events include solo and group concerts, performances of his works by others, as well as his appearances and participation in music-related conferences and festivals from the 1980s to the 2000s. This series also contains files Polansky had grouped himself by event, performance group, or subject, including topics such as dance, Gamelan music, an Australia concert tour, and Ostrava concerts. Files Polansky accumulated on groups he performed with include the New Kanon New Music Ensemble, the Berkeley Mandolin Ensemble, and DownTown Ensemble. Polansky also collected programs, announcements, calendars, and posters for Mills College and Dartmouth College performances dating from the 1980s to the 2000s, in which he was involved as a performer or organizer. Work files for select concerts, conferences, and festivals are described in Series V.
  - Astra, 1989, 1996-1997, 2000; cuid25316 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Australia, 1989; cuid25731 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Berkeley Mandolin Ensemble, 1982-1984; cuid25317 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Buy One for the Spare Parts, Presentation of HMSL (Hierarchical Music Specification Language), 1986; cuid25318 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Concert Calendars, 1991-2004; cuid25742 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Concerts, Conferences, and Festivals, 1976-1990s, undated; cuid25319 (Box 10, Folder 1-6, Box 74, Folder 6, Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Concerts, Conferences, and Festivals, 1990s, 2001-2002; cuid25320 (Box 11, Folder 1-6, Folder 1)
  - Concerts, Conferences, and Festivals, 2000-2008; cuid25321 (Box 12, Folder 1-6)
  - Concerts, Conferences, and Festivals, 2007-2012, undated; cuid25322 (Box 13, Folder 1-7, Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Concerts, Conferences, and Festivals, 2013; cuid25323 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Dance, 1979-1988; cuid25324 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Dartmouth College, 1991-2011, undated; cuid25325 (Box 14, Folder 3, Box 82, Folder 4, Box 84, Folder 5)
  - DownTown Ensemble, 1990, 2002-2006; cuid25326 (Box 14, Folder 4, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_6)
  - Gamelan, 1983-1994; cuid25327 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Gamelan Son of Lion, 1990; cuid25328 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - HMSL (Hierarchical Music Specification Language), 1995, undated; cuid25732 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Langton Concert, Program Notes, 1988; cuid25329 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Lonesome Road (The Crawford Variations) / World Premiere Concert, 1994, 1997; cuid25330 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Mills College, 1981-1993, 2012; cuid25331 (Box 14, Folder 9-11, Box 82, Folder 6, Box 84, Folder 5)
  - New Kanon New Music Ensemble, 1981-1982; cuid25332 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Ostrava Concert Programs, 2011; cuid25333 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Posters, 1984-1997; cuid25743 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Sound Recordings on Audiocassette, 1980-1994; cuid25860 (Box 98)
- Series III. Frog Peak Music, 1948, 1965-2011, undated; 10 Linear Feet in 1 carton, 15 manuscript boxes, 1 tall manuscript box, and 2 oversize flat boxes; 158 Megabytes in 218 computer files.; 19 audiocassettes; 2 Reels; 2 videocassettes (video 8); 2 videoreels (1/2 inch)
  The series contains office files for Frog Peak Music, as well as the office and client files for Lingua Press, a company absorbed by Frog Peak Music in 1995. A small selection of files on Lingua Press founder Kenneth Gaburo can also be found in this series.
  This series is organized into two subseries:
  Subseries A: General
  Subseries B: Lingua Press and Kenneth Gaburo
  - Subseries III. A. General, 1975-2011, undated; 1975-1995; 4 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 7 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box folder, and 1 tall manuscript box; 158 Megabytes in 218 computer files.; 19 audiocassettes
    Files listed in alphabetical order.
    Historical Note
    Frog Peak Music is a collective of experimental composers founded in 1982 by Larry Polansky and Jody Diamond. The organization is artist-run, devoted to publishing and producing experimental works and distributing artist-produced materials. The organization also has a CD label, as well as carries scores, recordings, writings, and other works by hundreds of artists internationally.
    This subseries contains correspondence, meeting notes, clippings, and publicity files generated by Frog Peak Music. Album production and promotional files include CD labels, advertisements, order catalogs, order forms, press releases, and reviews related to recordings released by Frog Peak Music. Materials in this subseries also relate to Polansky's albums produced and music published through Frog Peak Music. This subseries also includes Polansky's computer programming language HMSL (Hierarchical Music Specification Language) user manuals and related promotional material dating from the late 1980s and early 1990s. Material specifically related to the development of HMSL is in Series IV. This subseries also includes editor's drafts, sheet music, and notes, related to Polansky's contribution to Frog Peak's publication of the Ruth Crawford Seeger piece, The Adventures of Tom Thumb. Frog Peak Music artist and client files in this subseries contain correspondence, agreements, biographies, and purchase reports. Prominent artist and client files include Richard Ayres, Warren Burt, Crawling With Tarts, Philip Corner, Peter Garland, Dan Goode, Paul Paccione, Charles Shere, and James Tenney.
    - The Adventures of Tom Thumb, 2003-2004; cuid25531 (Box 31, Folder 1-6)
    - Allegro / Frog Peak Contract, 2011; cuid25369 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Ames, 1990; cuid25370 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - S. Armstrong, 1996; cuid25371 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Artifact, undated; cuid25372 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Artist Agreement Forms, 1987-1989; cuid25373 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Artist Payments Records / Ledgers, Other Printouts, 1988-1994; cuid25374 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Arts Publishing, 1993-1994; cuid25375 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Audiovisual Recordings, 1982-1986, 1991, 2001; cuid25870 (Box 115)
      1/2" Open Reel (Video), Count: 2
      Video8, Count: 2
    - Ayres, R., 1995; cuid25376 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Benary, 1992-1995; cuid25377 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Bischoff, 1988-1995; cuid25378 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - BMI, 1986-1995; cuid25379 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Bobrowski, 1995; cuid25380 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Jack Body, 1990; cuid25381 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Braun-Brumfield, 1986-1993; cuid25382 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Braxton, 1987; cuid25383 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Burt, 1992-1995; cuid25384 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Catalogs, 1988-1995, 2001; cuid25385 (Box 58, Folder 17, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_9)
    - CD Labels, 1987-2002; cuid25386 (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - CD Liner Notes, undated; cuid25387 (Box 58, Folder 19)
    - CD Review Flyers, 1991; cuid25388 (Box 58, Folder 20)
    - Chalmers, John, 1992-1996; cuid25390 (Box 58, Folder 22, Box 82, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1998-2008; cuid25391 (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - Cold Blue, 1990; cuid25389 (Box 58, Folder 21)
    - Collaborations Project, 1996-1999; cuid25888 (Box 59, Folder 12-13, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_8)
    - Computer Music Flyer, undated; cuid25392 (Box 58, Folder 24)
    - Corner, 1993-1996; cuid25393 (Box 58, Folder 25-26)
    - Crawling with Tarts, 1993-1995; cuid25394 (Box 58, Folder 27)
    - CRI, 1992-1993; cuid25395 (Box 58, Folder 28)
    - Curran, 1994; cuid25396 (Box 58, Folder 29)
    - Del Farra, 1991; cuid25397 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Dickmeyer, 1992; cuid25398 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Divisions, 1993; cuid25399 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Dorobo, 1995; cuid25400 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Erbe, Tom, 1994-1995; cuid25401 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Erikson-Magellan Music, 1992-1993; cuid25402 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Experimental Intermedia, 1994-1995; cuid25403 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Font Collection Info, undated; cuid25406 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Forlin / Rastascan, 1993; cuid25407 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Fritsch Feedback Studio, 1992-1996; cuid25404 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Frog Peak Flyers, Programs, Press, etc., 1985-1986, undated; cuid25405 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Frog Peak Rock Music Book, 1995; cuid25878 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Furnitures, 1993; cuid25408 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Gaburo / Lingua Press, 1992; cuid25409 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Gann, 1992-1995; cuid25410 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Garland, Peter, 1990-1995; cuid25412 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Gerrard, 1990-1993; cuid25411 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Gertraud Scholz Verlag, 1992-1993; cuid25413 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Gnazzo, 1993; cuid25414 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Goldstein, 1990-1995; cuid25415 (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Goode, Daniel, 1990-1995; cuid25416 (Box 59, Folder 22, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_10)
    - Hajdu, 1992; cuid25417 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Harrison, 1991-1995; cuid25418 (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - Hermes Beard Logo, undated; cuid25419 (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - HMSL (Hierarchical Music Specification Language) CD Contracts, 1993; cuid25420 (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - HMSL (Hiearchical Music Specification Language) Installation, 1989-1992; cuid25887 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_11)
    - HMSL (Hierarchical Music Specification Language) Press / Reviews, 1988-1992; cuid25421 (Box 59, Folder 27)
    - HMSL (Hierarchical Music Specification Language) Reference Manual, Version 3.12, 1987; cuid25422 (Box 59, Folder 28)
    - HMSL (Hierarchical Music Specification Language) Reference Manuals, 1991, 1993; cuid25423 (Box 60, Folder 1-3)
    - Horton, Jim, 1994; cuid25424 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Howell, Mark, 1998; cuid25425 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Innova, 1995; cuid25426 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Elise Kermani / Ishtar Mi Shinnah, 1999; cuid25427 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Kitsz, 1993; cuid25428 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - D. Krause, 1995; cuid25429 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Krinsky, Joy, 1993; cuid25430 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - La Berge, 1990-1995; cuid25431 (Box 60, Folder 11-12)
    - Lerman, A., 1990, 1995-1996; cuid25432 (Box 60, Folder 13, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_7)
    - Letters: Old Copies, 1988-1991; cuid25433 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Lingua Artist Letter, 1995-1996; cuid25434 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Logos: Frog Peak, undated; cuid25435 (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Lyon, 1993; cuid25436 (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Magwood, 1994; cuid25437 (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - D. Mahler, 1988-1995; cuid25438 (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - Main Street Museum Series, 1997-1999; cuid25439 (Box 60, Folder 20-21)
    - Margolis / Pogus Productions, 1991-1993; cuid25445 (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - Marquardt, 1996; cuid25440 (Box 60, Folder 23)
    - Marsanyi, 1995; cuid25441 (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - Meeting Notes, 2002-2003; cuid25443 (Box 60, Folder 26)
    - Mellers, Wilfred, 1994-1995; cuid25442 (Box 60, Folder 25, Box 98)
    - Meta + Hodos and META Meta + Hodos, 1986, 1992; cuid25876 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, cuid25444 (Box 60, Folder 27)
    - Morris, 1992; cuid25446 (Box 60, Folder 28)
    - Musicworks, 1992-1993; cuid25447 (Box 60, Folder 29)
    - Nagorcka, Ron, 1989-1994; cuid25448 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - New Instrumentation and Orchestration. An Outline for Study, 1986; cuid25875 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - NMA (Publishing), 1992-1995; cuid25449 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - No Replacement, 1994; cuid25450 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Oliveros Foundation, 1993; cuid25451 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Open Space, 1992-1993; cuid25452 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Ed Osborn, 1989-1992; cuid25453 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Paccione, 1992-1995; cuid25454 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Perkis, 1988-1990; cuid25455 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Personal Catalog Master / Larry Polansky, undated; cuid25456 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Peters, 1992-1994; cuid25457 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, Reviews, 1990, undated; cuid25458 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Plonsky, 1989-1996; cuid25459 (Box 61, Folder 12-13)
    - Plucked Strings Notes, 1986; cuid25460 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Pogus Productions, 1994-1995; cuid25461 (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Polansky: The Crawford Variations, undated; cuid25462 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - Polansky, 1993-1995, 2009; cuid25463 (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Pound, 1994-1995; cuid25464 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Povall, 1990-1995; cuid25465 (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Powell, 1993; cuid25466 (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Press List and Review List, undated; cuid25467 (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - Press Packet, 1989, undated; cuid25468 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Printed Matter, 1993-1994, 1998; cuid25469 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Rastascan / Robair, 1995; cuid25470 (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Red House, 1993-1994; cuid25471 (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Thomas Reed, 1992; cuid25472 (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Reid, Wendy, 1989; cuid25473 (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Review Notes, 1988; cuid25474 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Reviews, 1991-2005; cuid25475 (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Robert Rich (Soundspace), undated; cuid25476 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - E. Richards, 1991-1995; cuid25477 (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Rock Anthology, undated; cuid25478 (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Rosenbloom, 1988-1991; cuid25479 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - Sadra Packet, 1981-1992, 1994, undated; cuid25480 (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
    - Scholz, 1994; cuid25481 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Scratch, 1995; cuid25482 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Selected Compositions, 1980s; cuid25483 (Box 62, Folder 5-7)
    - Shaker Songs / Five Haiku, undated; cuid25484 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Shere, Charles, 1993-1995; cuid25485 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Shim, 1990-1994; cuid25486 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Skempton: Song 2 Contract, 2000; cuid25487 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - A Small Book of Rounds, 2005-2010; cuid25488 (Box 62, Folder 12-14)
    - Soundprints, 1995; cuid25489 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Sound Recordings on Audiocassette, 1980-1994; cuid25859 (Box 98)
    - Sound Recordings on Open Reel, 1984-1985; cuid25869 (Box 109)
      1/4" Open Reel (Audio), Count: 2
    - Stäbler, 1993-1994; cuid25490 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Sumner / Burning Books, 1994; cuid25491 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Sumner, 1995; cuid25492 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Tango, 1993; cuid25493 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Tenney [James], 1994-1996; cuid25494 (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - Thumpmusic CD, 1994-1996; cuid25495 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Trubee, 1995; cuid25496 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Verge, 1995; cuid25497 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - L. Wendt, 1989-1992; cuid25498 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Western Front, 1994; cuid25499 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Clive Wilkinson, 1994-1997; cuid25500 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - "Window on Music Publishing" Student Paper on Frog Peak Music History, 2000; cuid25501 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Wolff, 1985, undated; cuid25502 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Wood, Charles, 1995; cuid25503 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Young, Gayle, 1992-1995; cuid25504 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - XH, 1992; cuid25505 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Zukofsky / CP, 1993-1994; cuid25506 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Subseries III. B. Lingua Press and Kenneth Gaburo, 1948, 1965-1992, undated; 7.5 Linear Feet in 9 manuscript boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes
    This series is arranged in alphabetical order by file title. The inventory lists an alphabetical range of titles.
    Kenneth Gaburo founded Lingua Press in 1975. Dedicated to the promotion of unique artist-produced works in all media related to language and music, Lingua Press produced scores, books, records, audio tapes, videotapes, and films. After the death of Gaburo, the company was acquired by Frog Peak Music in 1995.
    This subseries includes Lingua Press inventory and office files as well as documentation of their acquisition by Frog Peak Music. Office files contain correspondence, distribution lists, artist copyright forms, letterhead, blank inventory sheets, and publication agreements dating from the 1970s and 1980s. Also in this subseries are proofs and layouts of Lingua Press publications assembled by founder Kenneth Gaburo, along with notebooks containing finances, mailing lists, and notes related to the business. This subseries also contains a small amount of Gaburo's personal correspondence, pocket calendars, address books, lecture notes, and requests for funding.
    - Add to Mailing List, 1982-1983; cuid25507 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Address Books -- All American Life and Casualty Company Insurance Policy, 1965-1980, undated; cuid25509 (Box 64, Folder 3-4)
    - Administrative Files, 1975-1990; cuid25508 (Box 63, Folder 14-18, Box 64, Folder 1-2)
    - Agreement Between Lingua Press and Frog Peak Music, 1995; cuid25728 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Allos Mock-Up Plates for Reference / Printer, 1980; cuid25510 (Box 64, Folder 5-7)
    - Back Orders -- California Business Permits, 1975-1985, undated; cuid25511 (Box 64, Folder 8-15)
    - Caracas -- Certificates of Copyright Registration and Signed Agreements, 1972-1992; cuid25512 (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
    - Collection II -- Collection III, 1972-1982; cuid25513 (Box 65, Folder 4-6)
    - Composer / Scores Publicity -- Contact List, 1981, undated; cuid25514 (Box 65, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1993, undated; cuid25515 (Box 65, Folder 9, Box 66, Folder 1-7, Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Dear Composer -- Gaburo Scores and Texts, 1948-1995, undated; cuid25516 (Box 67, Folder 2-14)
    - Event Posters, 1990, 1999; cuid25729 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Great Midwestern Bookshow, 1982-1983; cuid25517 (Box 68, Folder 1-2)
    - Inventory, Activities by Title, 1977-1982; cuid25518 (Box 68, Folder 3-6)
    - Invoices, 1979; cuid25519 (Box 68, Folder 7-9, Box 69, Folder 1-2)
    - Kenneth Gaburo Unpublished Manuscripts with Bob Paredes Annotations, 1986, undated; cuid25730 (Box 81, Folder 7-8)
    - Layout Sheets for Publications, 1976, undated; cuid25744 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Library Customer Files, 1975-1990, undated; cuid25520 (Box 69, Folder 3-18)
    - Linda Dusman Correspondence -- Merchandise Inventory Cost Figures, 1975-1992, undated; cuid25521 (Box 69, Folder 19-26)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965, 1976-1992; cuid25522 (Box 69, Folder 27, Box 70, Folder 1-2)
    - Museum Notes -- Orders, 1969-1986, undated; cuid25523 (Box 70, Folder 3-11)
    - Permissions to Use -- Theodore Front Musical Literature Correspondence / Administrative Files, 1970-2013; cuid25524 (Box 71, Folder 1-12)
- Series IV. Writings and Projects, 1949, 1953, 1976-2013, undated; 21.75 Linear Feet in 4 cartons, 21 manuscript boxes, 6 tall manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, and 3 oversize flat boxes; 20 Gigabytes in 13,106 computer files.; 72 audiocassettes; 24 sound cassettes (dat); 44 Reels; 4 videocassettes (vhs); 5 videocassettes (betamax)
  Files were arranged in alphabetical order by file title.
  This series contains paper documents, electronic files, and sound recordings related to Polansky's numerous writings and projects. As a reviewer, editor, and writer, Polansky wrote frequently on topics related to modern music and composers. Writing files in this series typically contain correspondence, edited drafts, and published articles with a significant amount regarding the works and theories of composer James Tenney. This series contains a significant amount of project files for the Ruth Crawford Seeger-related book The Music of American Folk Song... (2001) which include research, edited drafts, correspondence, song transcriptions, and digitized Seeger family photographs. Planning files for Seeger-related concerts and events are also in this series. Polansky's work files on a Harry Partch music transcription project includes annotated sheet music, research, and notes dating from the late 1970s and early 1980s. Documentation in this series on the development of Hierarchical Music Specification Language (HMSL), a computer program Polansky co-wrote with Phil Burk and David Rosenboom while teaching at Mills College, includes grant requests, user manual drafts, presentation notes/slides, old source code, code logs, articles, and notes from the 1980s to the 2000s. Additional material on the Frog Peak Music publication of the HMSL user manual and promotion is in Series III.A. Sound recordings and computer files related to Eine Kleine Gamelan Music, a group project using HMSL, is also in this series. During 1988 and 1989, Polansky and Jody Diamond worked on a Gamelan music project in Indonesia with native composers and musicians. This project is documented through notebooks, studio recording logs, and audio recordings of recording sessions. Polansky and Diamond eventually produced albums from this project, including Asmat Dream, Mana 689, and Karya. Polansky's career as a recording artist is documented in this series through paper and computer files; audio recordings of studio sessions and practices; recording session notes and logs; cd images and promotional material; and contracts. Of note are his recording sessions from the late 1990s to early 2000s for his 51 Melodies album and improvisation sessions with his group,Trio, which includes fellow musicians Christian Wolff and Kui Dong.
  - 1 / 1 The Quarterly Journal of the Just Intonation Network...Guest Editor, 1985; cuid25525 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 2 51's and 2 17's for Kenneth Gaburo, 1993; cuid25526 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 17 Gloomy Sentences, 1991; cuid25527 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 17 Memories of Bill, 2000; cuid25528 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 51 Melodies, 1998-2000; cuid25662 (Box 25, Folder 15, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_13, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_56)
  - $100 Guitar Project, 2012; cuid25529 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - About Moving, 1994; cuid25530 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Albums and Studio Session Sound Recordings on Digital Audio Tape (DAT), 1993-2003; cuid25864 (Box 102)
  - American Gamelan Institute CDs, undated; cuid25532 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Anita Feldman and Ann Rodiger Concert, 1982-1984; cuid25533 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Anna, Choir, 1997, 2001-2002; cuid25890 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_14)
  - Anna's Music Box, Computer Music Midi Software for Kids, 1997; cuid25534 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Anna's Music Box / The World's Longest Melody, 1996-1997; cuid25891 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_15)
  - Another You Recording Log, 1991; cuid25535 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Astrophony, 2001; cuid25892 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_16, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_57)
  - Audiovisual Recordings, 1978, 1986-1987, 1991; cuid25872 (Box 115)
    VHS, Count: 4 Betamax, Count: 5
  - Barlow (Commission Contract), 2007; cuid25536 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Bedhaya...(Solo Version) Recording Log, 1992; cuid25537 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Bedhaya Edition, Recording Log and Notes, 1995; cuid25538 (Box 15, Folder 15)